《越狱》前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break
我们要留下
We're staying.
让他们见鬼去
Give 'em hell.
比尔别这样
Phil, don't do this.
我把自己的一生都献给了这个国家
I've dedicated my life to this country.
还有卡罗琳
And Caroline
每张照片
Every photo,
每一份资料 全都消除掉
every file... get rid of it all.
比尔别这么做
Phil, don't do this.
你给盖瑞先生留了言
You left a message for Mr. Geary.
我会找到你的  你最好祈祷吧
I'm going to gut you, bow to stern.
我没有杀罗伊 盖瑞
I did not kill Roy Geary.
-巴格威尔陷害了我    -现在以一级谋杀罪
-Bagwell set me up.  -You are under
逮捕你
arrest  for the first degree murder
涉嫌杀害罗伊 盖瑞
of Roy William Geary.
我的心理医生跟我说
My therapist said
我必须要来面对你
that I need to confront you to
让你知道我有多么地感觉到自己被欺骗
let you know how betrayed I feel.
我们是警察
This is the Tribune police.
只要你做好你的事   我们就不会记得查尔斯 奥斯卡的事
Look, as long as you do your job with me, not a chance.
你也好回科罗拉多
And then you can go back to Colorado
去看你的儿子  还有家人
and visit your son and family.
不许你再提起他的名字
Don't you ever mention his name again.
后面有人在追我们怎么办?
What about your friend back there?
如果我们要越境...
If we're going to go down...
也许我们可以大摇大摆地过去
might as well go down swinging.
-莎拉    -迈克尔
-Sara.   -Michael?
差点就成了是吧?
Almost made it.
有人吗?
Hello.
是你吗  迈克尔?
Hello. Michael?
起来
Get up.
转过去
Turn around.
转过去!
Turn around!
如果你想杀了我们  阿力克斯
If you're going to murder us, Alex
动手的时候你应该盯着
you're going to have to look us
-我们的双眼      -闭嘴
in the eyes while you do it.     Shut up.
你要的是我  你也抓到我了
You want me, you got me.
- 让我弟弟走    - 你们俩我谁也不要
Let my brother go!   I don't want either of you.
我只是想要回我的生活!
I just want my life back!
那你打算杀掉两个无辜的人来换取?
You're going to kill two innocent men to get it, huh?
你说的没错
Absolutely.
我们是美国边境巡逻队
This is the United States Border Patrol.
放下武器并且站在原地
Drop the weapon and remain where you are.
美国边境巡逻队
United States Border Patrol.
扔下你的武器
Drop your weapon.
我是联邦探员  这些人是我的囚犯
I'm FBI. These men are in my custody.
我不管你是谁
I don't care who you are.
在我们查清楚之前
Until we verify,
把武器放下
you will drop your weapon
不然我们就把你放倒
or we will drop you.
你自己决定
Your choice.
把双手放在头上
Hands' on your head. Don't move.
有什么喝的吗?
You got anything to drink?
在后面找找
Check the back.
不明飞机  不明飞机
Unknown rider, unknown rider,
我们是缉毒组的
this is dea on guard.
立刻转到电台1145频率
Bring up frequency 1145.
啊哦!
Uh-oh.
啊哦?
Uh-oh?
什么意思?
What do you mean,"uh-oh"?
边境巡逻队追上我们了
Border patrol's on our ass, man.
我们还要多久才到墨西哥?
How long till we get to Mexico?
我们已经在墨西哥了  哥们儿
We're already in Mexico, papa.
我以为他们不能再追我们了
I thought they couldn't follow us
我们都跨过边境了
once we crossed the bord.
911以后就不再是这样了  兄弟
Hey, not since 9/11,hombre.
我们是缉毒组的
I repeat: This is dea on guard.
我们该怎么办?
What are we going to do?
唱圣歌并祈祷吧
Pull the chord, and pray.
才不要
Oh,hell, no.
如果我们试图降落这飞机      就肯定会被抓
Look,we try and land the plane,we're pinched for sure.
那如果我们跳伞呢?
And if we jump?
我们在沙漠的正中间
We're in the middle of the desert.
巡逻队要想发现我们得花上不少时间
Patrol have a hard time trying to find us once we land.
前提是我们能降落
If we land.
你肯定会降落的
Oh, you're going to land.
差别就是你怎么降落
It's just a matter of how hard.
祝你好运  兄弟
Good luck, amigo.
我们收到报告
We're receiving reports that
逃犯林肯·布伦斯和迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
escaped convicts Lincoln Burrows
在距离美墨边境以北几英里处刚刚被抓获
and Michael Scofield have been apprehended
联邦探员阿力克斯·马宏
Federal agent Alex Mahone
在美国边境巡逻队的帮助下
with assistance from the United States Border Patrol
在不久前将两人关押
took the men into custody just a short time ago.
现在很多消息都不明朗
Now, not a lot of information available at this time
但我们知道兄弟俩的被捕并非意外
but we do know the brothers were apprehended without incident
他们在试图穿越新墨西哥沙漠并离开美国 距离伊利诺伊州千里之外的地方被逮到了
while attempting to leave the country through the deserts of New Mexico quite a long way
也就是不到10天前他们
from Illinois's Fox River State Penitentiary
逃出的福克斯河监狱
where they escaped from less than ten days ago.
现在我们知道福克斯河的8名逃犯
The Fox River eight, as the group of convicts were once known
只剩4人在逃
are now down to four,
也就是本杰明麦尔斯·富兰克林
as only Benjamin Miles Franklin
费尔南多·苏克雷 查尔斯·波多斯基还有西奥多·巴格威尔
Fernando Sucre, Charles Patoshik and Theodore Bagwell
依然在逃
remain at large.
长官
Sir.
他刚听说了
He just heard.
而且他想见你
And he'd like to see you.
现在只剩4名逃犯
Convicts are now down to four
也就是本杰明麦尔斯·富兰克林
as only Benjamin Miles Franklin
费尔南多·苏克雷  查尔斯·波多斯基还有西奥多·巴格威尔依然在逃
Fernando sucre, Charles Patoshik and Theodore Bagwell remain at large.
一路顺风  先生们
Godspeed, gentlemen.
打扰下  士官
'Scuse me, sarge.
我在想不知道你能不能帮兄弟一个忙
I, uh, was wondering if you could, uh, help a brother out.
什么忙?
With what?
我刚刚从沙漠地区推广民主回来(伊拉克战争)
I only recently returned from delivering democracy to the desert and,
我在想你能不能告诉我
uh, I was wondering if you could tell me
什么地方能够做个假手臂吗？
how a guy goes about getting a hold of one of those prosthetic jobbies.
怎么在把你送回来前他们没把你整好?
What, they make you whole before they shipped you back?
打个比方吧  医生光知道铺床
Well, let's just say the doctor made the bed.
但却不叠被子(做事情半调子)
He just neglected to tuck in the sheets.
最好的办法就是去退伍军人服务处
Best thing for you to do is go on down there to va.
在那儿排队
Get in line.
-就这么简单?     -没错
That simple?     Yeah.
直到他们寄给你帐单
Till they send you the bill
而你则得去想办法怎么付钱
and you got to figure out how to pay.
华盛顿那帮畜牲把我们送出去为他们卖命  却没人为我们卖命
Those bastards up there in Washington send us off to fight for them; not a damn one of 'em fights for us.
这简直就是犯罪
And that is a crime.
但对我来说走运的是
But luckily for me, uh...
钱不是问题
money is not the issue.
是吗?
Is that right?
在此之前我是不是有什么特别的表格要填?
Any particular, uh, forms I might need in order to qualify?
你知道吗  啥也不问啥也不说先生?
You know what, Mr. Don't ask, don't tell?
既然你有办法自己把头发染成那样
You figured out how to dye that hair of yours up like
跟个娘门儿似的
like a nancy all by yourself,
你肯定也有办法为你自己那断手接个假肢
you sure as hell can figure out how to get a prosthetic for that stump of yours by yourself.
是啊  我想我知道该怎么做了
Yeah, I think I got a pretty good idea where to start.
拉斯克鲁斯  新墨西哥州   边境巡逻队哨所基地
LAS CRUCES, NEW MEXICO  BORDER PATROL HOLDING FACILITY
伊利诺伊州 朱丽 福克斯河州立监狱
JOLIET ILLINOIS  Fox River STATE PENITENTIARY
现在在我身边的是
I'm here with
埃德 普维卡  福克斯河监狱的
ED Pavelka, the new warden
新任监狱长  这里也就是计划中
of Fox River penitentiary
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德和林肯·布伦斯
where Lincoln Burrows and Michael Scofield are scheduled to
将于明天某些时候被遣返的地方
be returned to sometime tomorrow.
狱长  越狱发生于林肯·布伦斯
Now, warden, the escape happened a mere two days
将被执行死刑的前2天
before Burrows was scheduled to be put to death.
他本来就还有1天时间
He's already been granted one day
你认为他是否还会有更多的时间?
do you anticipate any further?
林肯·布伦斯是一名已经判决的谋杀犯
Lincoln Burrows is a convicted murderer.
他的逃脱
His escape
使全国平民的生命处于危险之中
has endangered the lives of civilians across this country.
他不是个名人
He is not a celebrity.
也不是个烈士
He is not a martyr.
我可以向你保证不管之前  他受到多少宽容的对待
I can assure you that whatever leniency was afforded him
还有在福克斯河旧管理阶层之下的其他犯人们
and the her prisoners under the old regime at Fox River
所有行为都不会再得到容忍
will no longer be tolerated.
等待布伦斯先生的  将是陪审团所要求的
The only thing that Mr. Burrows can expect is
迅速执行死刑
what a jury of his peers demanded: A speedy execution.
那迈克尔 斯克菲尔德呢?
And Michael Scofield?
因为他设计的越狱
With his escape,
帮助并且教唆
the aiding and abetting charges the felonies
那些他纠集起来的犯人
he's racked up along the way
加上他原来所犯的罪行    恐怕斯克菲尔德先生
on top of his original sentence, I'd say Mr. Scofield will be spending
必须要在监狱里度过余生了
the rest of his life behind bars.
谢谢
Thank you.
芝加哥  FBI指挥中心
CHICAGO ILLNOIS   FBI FIELD OFFICE
谁来接马宏的电话?
Who's got Mahone?
恭喜你  长官
Congratulations, sir.
你们收到什么了?
What do you got?
从伊利诺伊监狱部门打来的电话
A call from the Illinois doc.
他们派了一大队人马
They're sending a huge contingent
来接布伦斯和斯科菲尔德 然后把他们带回福克斯河
down there to collect Burrows and Scofield, take them back to Fox River personally.
告诉他们这是联邦案件
Remind them this is a federal case and
我们会负责犯人的转移工作  现在...
we'll handle the transport. Now...
我说了  但今年是选举年  蛋糕很大
I did. But it's an election year, collar this big
每个人都想分一杯羹  新狱长直接
everybody wants a piece. The warden called in a favor
向联邦调查局长要的  他同意了       所以我们就照办
to the bureau chief; he okayed it, so here we are.
他们大概一小时后应该到了
Should be there in about an hour.
我要进到
I want to be placed in the
犯人押送车里
prisoner transport vehicle.
为什么?
What for?
你照办就是了
Just get it done.
长官  这些可是大鱼
Sir, these were the big fish.
你把他们抓住了
And you brought 'em in.
你应该为此感到高兴
You should feel good about that.
是啊...
Yeah...
是啊
yeah.
至少我们还在一起
Well, at least we're together.
是啊至少如此
Yes, there is that.
你在想什么?
What are you thinking?
我在想老爸
I'm thinking about the old man.
他试图做的那些事  你知道
What he tried to do, you know.
当你被关在笼子里你就 不可能大摇大摆地走了
Tough to go down swinging when you're locked in a box.
一切都还没结束呢
This isn't over yet.
我们有权打个电话
We're entitled to a phone call.
我们给莎拉打个电话  而她有那些信息
We make that one call to Sara and she has the information
爸爸说她有
dad said she has
我们可以在这一切继续下去之前
we can get you exonerated before
-让你无罪释放   -别
-this whole thing goes down.    -No.
我们有权打个电话
We're entitled to a phone call.
你们有权乖乖的蹲在那里
You're entitled to precisely squat
直到你们被正式拘捕
until you're officially in custody.
而那必须要等你们被送回福克斯河之后
And that won't happen until you're back in Fox River.
所以去老实坐着
So sit tight.
还没结束
It's not over yet.
还没
Not yet.
从这里到伊利诺伊州还有好多路要赶
A lot of ground to cover between here and Illinois.
我是说
I mean,
我们能活着回到福克斯河的机会有多大呢?
what are the chances we even make it back to Fox River alive?
在电视上看到你了  阿力克斯
Saw you on the news, Alex.
是吗?
Did you?
还有那两兄弟
The brothers too.
他们比我盼望见到的要...
They were a little more, um...
更生龙活虎了一点
breathing than I had hoped.
边境巡逻队突然出现  我无能为力
Yeah, well, border patrol showed up. Nothing I could do.
真的吗?
Really?
布伦斯和斯科菲尔德
Burrows and Scofield,
从你站的地方能看到他们吗?
can you see them from where you are?
可以
Yeah.
那动手杀了他们
Then put a bullet in their heads.
他们被看护着
They're being watched.
我不管
I don't care.
是武装了的守卫
By armed guards.
如果让他们回到福克斯河      一切都完了
They make it back to Fox River, it is over.
我们都完了
For all of us.
在这个国家里没有什么 比一个有好故事的坏人更吸引人的了
There's not much more this country loves than a bad man with a good story.
你觉得在有人给他们发言的机会前我们还有多少时间?
How much longer do you think it'll be before someone puts a microphone in front of them?
你在听吗?
Hey, are you listening?
好吧  这里有如此多的警卫
Okay, with the security here,
你要我做的事情等于自杀
what you're asking me to do is tantamount to suicide.
你明白我在说什么吗?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
我不是在要求你去做什么事
I wasn't asking anything.
那样会让你觉得你还有说话的余地
That would imply you had a say in the matter.
解决这些事  你就差不多可以回家了      阿力克斯
Pull this off and you're halfway home, Alex.
你还记得家是什么样吧  是吗?
You remember what home is like. Don't you?
西头大街900号 白色栅栏  红色的门
900 west end Avenue. White fence. Red door.
离我家人远点!
Stay away from my family!
有点东西粘在你的...
You got a little something on your, uh...
不是...我来帮你吧
here, let me.
原谅我的直接  我...
Pardon my forwardness, I was...
没关系  谢谢你
it's okay. Thank you.
一般情况下我是不会管的  只是...
Normally I wouldn't intervene, it's just...
昨天我下班回家后
yesterday when I got home from work
我发现看上去好象
I found what looked like
巴西的热带丛林
the brazilian rain forest
卡在我的两颗门牙之间
lodged between my two front teeth.
我能想到的就是
And all I could think about
肯定有很多人看见了...
was the number of people who must've seen and not...
却没有一个人能好心地告诉我
not a damn one of them had the decency to tell me.
微度齿隙
Mild diastema.
什么?
Excuse me?
在你的8号和9号齿之间
It's a slight gap between
有一个小的缝隙
your eight and nine.
就是你的两颗门牙
Your two front teeth.
有时候它就会象磁铁一样
And that it sometimes can act as a magnet
把一些食物...
for food like...
象椰菜  吞拿鱼还有米
broccoli and tuna and sometimes rice.
或者一些调料吸进去
Or relish.
你这些都知道?
All this and brains, too?
你是牙医还是什么...?
What are you, a dentist or...
我?不是  当然不是
Me? No, hardly, no.
我不可能是
I could never.
我的前夫  他是...
My ex, my ex-husband, he was...
混球?
a bastard?
没错
That too.
你去过意大利吗 恩...?
Have you ever been to italy, uh...
- 丹妮斯   - 丹妮斯
Denise. Denise,
真是个好听的名字
that's a lovely name.
你知道  在意大利
You know, in italy,
他们每天中餐都要有葡萄酒
they have wine every day with lunch.
而在我们这个国家呢?
And what do we do in this country?
我们靠咖啡因和碳酸来下饭
We power our food down with caffeine, carbonation
还有高热果糖和糖浆
and high fructose corn syrup.
没人再花时间来享受了
No one ever takes the time to enjoy things anymore.
丹妮斯  你是否愿意
Denise, would you do me the honor
和我一起来享受
of "enjoying"
剩下的午餐?
the rest of your lunch with me?
我想我会喜欢的
I think I'd like that.
白酒还是红酒?
White or red?
堪萨斯州 克雷县    地方法院
在有限的经济条件下
And with limited financial resources
他不可能有坐飞机逃跑的可能...
he poses no flight risk...
除非他不愿意
unless he'd rather not
接受谋杀审讯
stand trial for capital murder.
被告已经显示了他在有限的经济条件下
The defendant has shown great resourcefulness in
穿越全国的能力
being able to travel across country
仅用了很少的钱
with little money.
没理由说他不会再做一遍
There's no reason he couldn't do it again.
如果你们不相信我
If you don't want to believe me,
相信贝利克先生自己的话吧
believe Mr. Bellick.
你个该死的杂种
You thieving son of a bitch.
你最好跪下向上帝祈祷
You better get down on your knees and pray to god that
最好别让我找到  因为一旦让我找到
I never find you because if I do,
记住我的话  我会
mark my words: I will
把你开膛破肚
gut you bow to stern.
他保证了要杀死盖瑞先生
He promised to kill Mr. Geary
并且信守了自己的诺言
and then he kept that promise.
象被告这样的人
A man like the defendant
不应该被留在社会上
should not be out in society.
我同意
I concur.
不许保释
Bail denied.
会是谁?
Who would that be?
只会是一个人
Only one person.
迈克尔  是我 听着  这个电话
Michael, it's me. Listen,
昨晚上响了  我接了
this phone rang last night and I went to answer it,
但是我什么也没听到  我在想
but I couldn't hear anything  and l-
是不是你?...
I wonder if maybe it was you?
上帝啊 我现在不知道自己该做什么
Oh, god, I don't know what I should do right now.
我不知道是不是该留个言
I don't know if I should leave a message or
但我又不知道那边现在是谁在听...
who might be listening to this, but...
我...
um, I, uh...
我要知道你没事
I need to know that you're okay.
要你知道我有事
I need you to know that I'm not.
在吉拉我并没离开你
I didn't leave you in Gila.
有事情发生了  我...
Something happened to me and I don't...
我不知道
um, I don't know
现在该做什么也不知道该去哪儿
what to do right now. I'm not too sure where to go,
但我知道你是我唯一可以信任的人
but I know that you're the only person I can trust
我希望你...
and I need you to, um...
我希望你没事...
I need you to be okay and, um...
并且我也需要你
and I need you.
准备开始边境巡逻队移交工作
亚力山大 马宏  联邦调查局的
Alexander Mahone, bureau.
这些是我的囚犯我要亲自
These are my prisoners and I will be personally escorting them
在他们的车上押送他们
in their transfer vehicle.
你可以在护送车里跟着...
You can follow in the chase car...
我想你没听到我说的
I don't believe you heard me.
- 我必须要在他们的...   - 唯一允许进入
I'll be accompanying them in their...   the only people allowed in the van
那辆车的只有司机
are the driver
还有两名受训过的合格警卫
and two guards who've been trained
在囚犯运输过程中
and certified in prison transport.
你一定要我找你上司来压你吗?
Are you really going to make me go over your head?
去找吧我甚至可以帮你打电话
I'll even dial the phone for you.
这可是标准程序
Now look, this is standard procedure,
马宏探员  我们必须
agent Mahone. We need to
让事情尽可能的在我们控制之下
keep that environment as controllable as possible.
插手的人越多就越难控制
The more bodies, the less control.
这两人
These men
可能知道
may have knowledge of
其他逃犯的位置
the location of the other escapees.
你要知道  我...
This is knowledge that I...
必须要完成我的工作
I need to do my job.
而我的工作是保证安全
And my job is to ensure the safe and
并顺利的运送这两名囚犯
successful transfer of these two prisoners.
护送车就在外面
Chase vehicles are right outside.
我们正在为您现场直播林肯·布伦斯和
We're coming to you live as brothers
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德兄弟正在被边境巡逻队
Lincoln Burrows and Michael Scofield
带出囚室...
are being led from the border patrol holding cell...
你最好有合理的解释
there better be a damn good reason
为什么这两兄弟还活者
why those brothers are still alive.
日子不好过了  比尔?
Bad day, Bill?
抱歉  我还以为是某个还存在的人打来的
Sorry, I thought this was someone who still existed.
肉干生意怎么样  欧文?(参见第一季  凯勒曼的伪装身份)
How's the jerky business, Owen?
事实上现在这会儿很不错
Actually, it's looking pretty good right about now.
你再打一次我这个号码  你就死定了
You call this number again, you're a dead man.
其实如果你今天杀不了布伦斯和斯科菲尔德你也死定了
Actually, you don't kill Burrows and Scofield today,so are you.
你我都知道的  而你很走运
You know it and I know it, and luckily for you
我知道怎么救你的小命(用扬声器)
I know how to save your ass.
那两兄弟已经上路了
The brothers are already being transferred.
你太晚了
You're too late.
实际上  那运输车正是你想他们呆的地方
Actually, that transport van is exactly where you want them to be, Bill.
为什么?
Why?
为什么? 你想要我帮忙 你就得让我复职
Why? You want my help, Bill, I want my job back.
也就是说要向总统直接汇报
That means direct access to the president.
我也只需要向她汇报
I report only to her.
你在做梦  保罗  再见
You're reaching, Paul. Good-bye.
别想把我抛开  比尔
Don't shut me out, Bill.
你觉得布伦斯和斯科菲尔德对这个政府是个威胁?
You think Burrows and Scofield are a threat to this administration?
我知道卡罗琳 雷纳德做过的每一件事
I know everything Caroline Reynolds has done.
每一件事
Everything.
在你感到害怕之前  我只是想
Now, before you panic, all I'm asking
能够再去完成我的工作
is to be allowed to finish the job that I started.
向总统还有你证明
To prove to the president and to you
对这个政府来说我还是有用的
that I'm still an asset to this administration.
(计划?)
你有什么计划?
What's your plan?
在伊利诺伊监狱部门我有个内应
I have an old associate in the Illinois doc.
他们负责押送
They're heading up the transfer.
这需要不只一个内部人员
It's going to take more than one guy on the inside.
如在合适的位置  一个就够了
Not if the guy's in the right place.
比尔  你给我句话
Bill, you give me the go-ahead on this
那两兄弟一走进车
when those brothers get in the van
这就是他们能做的最后一件事了
it'll be the last thing they ever do.
我以前从来没做过那个
I have never done that before.
那我想我们是弥补了一些失去的时光了
Then I guess we were making up for some lost time.
我必须要问问  山姆  你是否...
I have to ask, Sam, are you, uh...
是否结婚了或什么?
are you married or something?
我?  没有
Me?  No.
- 是什么让你觉得...?       - 得了吧
- What makes you think...  - Come on.
虽然我很普通  但我也不是个傻子
I may be plain, but I'm not a fool.
通常和我在一起的男人
Usually the men I end up with are
只是在寻找一些...你知道...
just looking for something, you know...
余兴
on the side.
丹妮斯  我唯一感兴趣的
Denise, the only "side" I'm interested in,
是内在
is the inside.
而你的内在...
And that place within you...
是不普通的
is not plain.
我要回去上班了
I have to get back to work.
真的要去吗?
Do you really?
今晚是我负责关门
I have to close tonight.
然后我去接你如何?
How 'bout I pick you up after?
我们可以一起吃晚饭
We can have dinner.
- 你确定吗?      - 丹妮斯...
- Are you sure?  - Denise...
非常确定
I insist.
是我
Yeah
好消息  你可以脱身了
Good news. You're off the hook.
凯勒曼有队人手准备在车队上行动
Paul Kellerman has a team ready to move on the caravan
只要一到阿拉布克
just outside of Albuquerque.
好的
Okay.
那我们该怎么做?
So where does that leave us?
等他们开始行动  肯定有一会儿会很混乱
When it goes down, there's sure to be a moment or two of chaos.
会有很多困惑  还有很多子弹在飞
A certain amount of confusion, lots of bullets flying.
我要你能保证保罗 凯勒曼吃到一颗
I need you there to make sure Paul Kellerman catches one.
现在就开始掩盖你的行动是不是早了点?
It's a little early to be covering your tracks, isn't it?
我们的约定只包括那些逃犯
The escapees... that was our deal.
就这么多
That's all.
是吗
Right.
我们的约定
Our deal.
帮我回忆一下
Refresh my memory.
我们的约定是否应该以布伦斯和斯科菲尔德
Was our deal supposed to end with Burrows and Scofield
回到监狱为完结呢还是...
going back to prison or...
以他们脑袋中枪为完结呢?
bleeding from a hole in their heads?
我们在给你机会来把事情做好  阿力克斯
We're giving you a chance to make this right, Alex.
就让凯勒曼来搞定
Just let Kellerman take care of it.
让他当我们的奥斯华(注 谋杀肯尼迪的嫌犯)
Let him be our Oswald.
那就是说让我当你们的杰克 罗比(注 在大庭广众之下枪杀了奥斯华的人)
Then, that makes me your Jack Ruby.
杰克 罗比是一个人单干
Jack Ruby was working alone.
你身后可有整个美国政府
You've got the support of the United States government
当你靠山  阿力克斯
behind you, Alex.
祝你在阿拉布克好运
Good luck in Albuquerque.
(解决掉凯勒曼)
(Retire Kellerman)
我保证  长官  这一切很快都会结束的
I promise, sir, this will all be over shortly
马上都会恢复正常的
and it will be back to business as usual.
你后悔吗?
Do you regret it?
什么?
What?
在知道今天这种局面后   你是否后悔救我?
Knowing what you know now, do you regret helping me?
换了是你  你也会为我做相同的事
You'd have done the same thing for me.
你觉得吗?
You think?
我知道的
I know.
你没回答我的问题
You didn't answer the question.
我并不后悔我的举动
I don't regret the act.
只是对事情的发展感到遗憾
Just how it turned out.
我们现在是被控诉涉嫌谋杀
We've got a premeditated murder on our hands.
你想偷那笔钱
You wanted to steal money and
然后杀了唯一的证人
then kill the only witness.
你是我的律师还是他们的?
Are you my attorney or theirs?
我告诉你了我什么也没干
I told you I didn't do anything.
我只是在跟你解释他们认为发生了什么
No, I'm just explaining their theory of what happened.
你对警察的解释是你没杀盖瑞
Your explanation to the cops that you didn't kill Geary
因为你忙着在偷
because you were too busy trying to steal
那属于国家的500万
five million in federally insured money.
这样做恐怕并不明智
Probably not the best move.
但还是有好消息
But there is good news.
是什么?
What's that?
地区法官愿意达成个协议
The DA is willing to offer a deal.
25年
25 years.
不要
No.
布拉德  他们会撤销谋杀起诉
Brad, they'll drop the capital charge.
- 就不会有死刑了    - 不要
- No death penalty. - No.
等我出来我就65岁了
I'd be almost 65 when I get out.
但你还是能出来
But you'd get out.
如果这案子送去审讯
If this case goes to trial,
你有很大机会会被判死刑
there's an excellent chance you're sentenced to death.
我见过很多这种情况了  布拉德
Now, I've been doing this a while, Brad,
这些事从来不会有好的结果
these things never go down good.
如果是整个体系都针对你
When the system wants you,
他们肯定能击败你  方法不同而已
they get you, one way or another.
那这个约定必须要包括一点
Part of the deal's got to be
我要在伊利诺伊服刑
I do my time in Illinois,
那样我就能和我妈妈在一起了
so I can be with my mom.
他们要把我们带到哪儿去?
Where are they taking us?
另一个寄养的家庭
Another foster home.
我不想走  我喜欢这里
I don't want to go. I liked it there.
我知道你喜欢
I know you did.
是因为你
It's 'cause of you.
所以他们才要我们又搬  是吧?
The reason they're making us move, isn't it?
因为你又惹什么麻烦了
'Cause you were getting in trouble again.
是的  我很抱歉
Yeah, and I'm sorry.
似乎我这一辈子都是在把你拖进麻烦中
Seems like I've been dragging you into trouble my whole life.
也把我从一些麻烦中拖出来过
Pulled me out of some, too.
是啊
Yeah
是我
Yerh
阿力克斯  我是保罗 凯勒曼
Alex. Paul Kellerman.
你和比尔 金谈过了吗?
Have you spoken with Bill Kim?
是的
Yeah,
是的他跟我说过了
he filled me in.
你要在阿拉布克行动
You're staging in Albuquerque.
现在听我说
Now, listen.
我现在加入
Me jumping in at this point.
并不代表
It in no way reflects
我对你做的工作有什么想法
my feelings about the job you've been doing.
我只想你明白这点
I just wanted you to know that.
当然
Of course.
只要我们把活儿做好
So long as we get the job done.
我们都可以回到各自的家人中去  对吧?
And we all get to go back to our families, right?
越快越好
The sooner the better.
那有什么是我要知道的吗?
So what do I need to know?
如我们昨天所报道的那样
在经过了9天的逃亡后
逃犯中的林肯·布伦斯和迈克尔·斯科菲尔德
两名福克斯河8人越狱事件的主谋
被美墨边境的巡逻队逮捕
并将于今天被送回福克斯河州立监狱
官方表示布伦斯的因谋杀总统的兄弟
特伦斯 斯坦德曼的死刑将会被重新安排
提前到下周的某一时间
因为帮助教唆其他犯人越狱
布伦斯的弟弟迈克尔斯克菲尔德
将会面临...
阿拉布克  新墨西哥州
Albuquerque, New Mexico
前面发生什么事了?
What's going on out there?
我去看看
Let me go check.
- 看见什么了?       - 会告诉你的
- What do you see?  - I'll let you know.
移动这卡车
How much time is it going
要花多少时间?
to take to move the semi?
我的人已经做忙着解决了
I've got my men working on it now.
前面出什么事了?
What's going on up there?
你很着急吗  囚犯?
Are you in a hurry, convict?
我们需要帮手去把障碍排除
Hey, we need some help getting this rig out of the road.
林肯
Linc.
好吧
All right,
我们先把手铐摘掉
let's say we get the cuffs off.
然后往哪儿跑?
Where do we go?
那儿
There.
这有点太简单了
That's too easy.
来吧来吧  迈克尔  快动手啊
Come on. Come on, Michael, take it.
快点 快点
Come on，Come on
拿钥匙
Take it.
拿上  然后跑
Take it and run.
让我们仔细想想
Let's think about this.
这钥匙就意外地掉下了
The keys are accidentally left out,
那门就这么意外地开着
the door is accidentally left open.
这是我们唯一的机会
It's our only shot.
这是他们唯一的机会
It's their only shot.
他们不能杀我们
They don't have an excuse to kill us
除非我们提供个理由给他们
unless we give it to them.
情况如何?
How are we doing?
目前还没动静
Nothing so far.
什么动静也没有?
None?
他们在说话  仅此而已
They're talking, that's all.
如果5分钟内他们还不上钩
If they haven't bitten in five minutes,
你去卡车那里说问题解决了
you haul the semi, you tell them it's fixed.
然后把路恢复
You release traffic.
然后呢?
And do what?
阿力克斯 要想兔子跳起来你就动动萝卜
If you want the rabbit to hop, you move the carrot, Alex.
你来了
You showed.
一个绅士总是说话算话
A gentleman always does.
我们去哪儿吃呢?
Where are we going to eat?
随便哪个你内心向往的地方
Wherever your heart desires.
你知道我有点小事情
You know, there's just one teensy-tiny thing
想让你帮个忙
I been meaning to ask.
任何事都行
Anything.
要知道更新的地址应该是保密的
You know, forwarding addresses are supposed to be confidential.
我其实不该这么做的
I really shouldn't be doing this.
其实...
我们今天下午做的很多事
You shouldn't have been doing a lot of
都是你不应该做的
the things we did this afternoon,
但是
but, uh,
我们俩还没因此受到什么惩罚
neither of us has been smited down yet.
找到了
There she is.
我想你的表亲
I'd imagine your cousin'll be pretty surprised
肯定会对舅舅留下的这笔钱感到意外的
to hear about the money her uncle left her.
这点你可以肯定
You can be certain of it.
山姆  希望你不介意我问你  但...
Sam, I hope you don't mind me asking, but, um,
你的手
your hand.
是出了什么事?
What happened to it?
对不起
I'm sorry.
我并不想让你感到不愉快
I didn't want to make you feel uncomfortable or nothing.
我只是...
I just...
想了解你
I want to know you.
我只是想了解你的全部...
I want to know everything about you, and...
如果现在的你只是其中一部分
if this is a part of who you are,
那我想知道是怎么...
then I want to know how it...
上帝啊
oh, dear god.
(通缉)
我真希望你没看见那个
I really wish you hadn't seen that.
我是这么想的
Okay, here's what I'm thinking.
你和一些人
You and some of the boys
你们想办法调到单独囚室去
get yourselves transferred over to ad seg.
那样的话我们就能每天
That way, we can spend our days
玩玩拼字游戏或者看看体育频道
playing scrabble and watching sportscenter.
- 听我说队长     - 然后在大概
- Look, cap'n... - then, in about
一年半左右你就推荐我去
a year and a half or so, you're gonna recommend me
做外面的劳改项目
for one of those work-release programs.
这样我就能每天
Then, I can sweat off the rest of my time
叉叉干草晒晒太阳
heaving hay and getting sun.
-那个...     - 虽然这还不是自由  但也差不多了
- That's...  - it ain't freedom, but it's damn close.
是不是这就是你要求
Is that why you requested
被送到这里来的原因?
to be sent here?
要是我去别的地方...
I go anywhere else...
作为一个前任狱警  我死定了
as a former co, I'm dead man.
但这里我有兄弟照顾我
But here I got men to watch my back.
给我最好的待遇...
Get me the finest accommodations...
他们不会把你分到单独囚室去的
they're not putting you in ad seg.
我不管他们把我分到哪里去
I don'care where they're putting me.
只要想办法把我弄到单独囚室去就好
Just take me to ad seg.
这里和以前不同了  队长
It's not like it used to be, cap'n.
狱警不再在这里有大权了
The cos don't run the game here anymore.
- 什么意思?           - 新来的狱长
- What do you mean?   - This new warden.
他要采取严厉措施
He's cracking down.
为了证明他的决心
And to prove he's serious about
作为优先处理的对象
showing preferential treatment,
他要拿你作为示范
he's making an example out of you.
这是怎么回事?
Lou, what the hell is this?
全面管理
General pop.
欢迎回来  老大
Welcome home, boss.
索诺兰沙漠  墨西哥 美墨边境以南40英里处
Sonoran desert, Mexico 40miles south of the US/Mexico border
好了  所有人  准备出发
okay, everybody, we're moving out.
机会就要没了 迈克尔,一旦那车开走  我们就...
Window's close, Michael. Once the truck moves, we're...
如果我们现在跑就等与给了他们
if we run now, we give them permission
开枪打我们的许可
to put a bullet in our heads.
我们留下  一周内我就死了
We stay, I'm dead within the week,
而你要在监狱里度过余生
and you're locked up for life.
或者等他们再找到机会来干掉你
Or until they find a way to get to you.
相信我  他们会的
And, believe me, they will.
如果我们会到监狱  我们还会有几天时间
If we go back to prison, we'll have a few extra days.
我们还有机会联系上莎拉
We'll have a chance to contact Sara.
我们不知道莎拉在哪儿
We don't know where Sara is.
莎拉也可以死了  迈克尔
Sara may be dead, Michael.
我们离开这里  我只知道一个办法
Let me get us out of here the only way I know how.
拼死一搏?
Fighting?
是的
Yeah
拿钥匙
Get the keys.
开始了开始了
Here we go. Here we go.
收到
Copyhat.
好的我们开始动手了
All right, we're on.
注意点
Heads up.
控制住车队
Hold traffic.
你知道我们对那门后的情况一无所知
You know we have no idea what's behind that door.
没错
Nope.
你准备好了吗?
You ready?
没有  你呢?
No. You?
没有
No.
我们走
Let's go.
但愿这里有别的出口
Just pray there's another way out of here.
这边走
This is way
他们进去了
Hey, they're in.
他们向你直奔过去
And they're heading straight for you.
有武器吗?
Armed?
没有
No.
你在哪儿?  我来支援你
Where are you? I'll back you up.
一直走
Just keep moving.
只要他们一直在你面前跑
As long as they're running from you,
就会一直跑到我这里来
they're running toward me.
他们就会被困死
They're boxed in.
好的
Yeah
南丝市  堪萨斯州
Ness city, Kansas
稍等一下
Hold on one sec.
我能用支票收这些吃的吗?
Can I write a check for the food?
因为我没有...
'Cause I don't have...
你好啊  郝兰德太太
Hello, Mrs. Hollander.
俗话说好女人
They say a good woman
很难找
is hard to find.
如果这是真的  那你一定是非常
Well, if that's true, you must be very,
非常...
very...
非常好
very good.
别害怕
Don't be frightened.
泰迪回来了
Teddy's home.
他们绕了个道  向地面去了
They're improvising, heading toward the surface.
往哪儿走?
Where to?
我不知道
I don't know.
听着如果我们万一出了什么事
Look, if something happens to us
如果我们被分开了 然后有一个人没能逃脱
if we get separated or one of us doesn't make it,
答应我你要去找莎拉
promise me you'll find Sara.
我们会逃脱的
We're gonna make it.
答应我
Just promise me.
我保证  走吧
I promise. Come on.
别动!
Don't move
雷纳德总统毁了你们的人生
President Reynolds ruined your life.
她也毁了我的
She ruined my life.
你们想把那贱人拉下台么?
You want to take that bitch down?
你们刚刚找到了个内部盟友  但我们现在必须马上走
You just found your inside man, but it's got to be right now.
我们走!
Let's go.
快!
Now!